RACHAEL WHITEFIELD



WFB DEVELOPER

CONTACT



619.977.8770



rachael.whitefield@gmail.com



github.com/RachaelWhitefield



www.linkedin.com/in/rachael-whitefield/

SUMMARY

Vivacious front-end web developer with an extensive background in business ownership and management. Passionate about integrating simple yet sophisticated designs as well as an appreciation for approaching programming challenges from different angles. Expertise managing business relationships and administering issue resolution to create better user interface experiences.

EDUCATION

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT CODING BOOTCAMP

University of Denver 2019

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JAVASCRIPT
- REACT
- GIT
- MATERIALIZE
- BOOTSTRAP
- Verbal Communication
- Working Independently
- Team Oriented
- Attention to Detail

PROJECTS

BABES IN BRUNCHLAND

Your Local Brunch Finder

Deployed at: https://savannahisrael.com/BabesInBrunchland/index.html

Looking for a brunch place close by? Use the Babes in Brunchland app to put in your zip code and desired price point to find a restaurant nearby with a 4.2 Zomato rating or higher using Yelp's API. Each result will show details, images, and a Google map of the location. A custom invitation can also be created and uploaded to share with your friends.

- Team Leader
- Front End Designer

GET STONED

Metaphysical Stone Index

Deployed at: https://glacial-journey-69057.herokuapp.com/

If you are curious about knowing more about stones and their metaphysical properties, this is the app for you. Log in to learn more about the characteristics of various stones and save your favorites from our custom-built API. Don't forget to have a rune reading while you're there.

- Built the login authentication code
- Front End Designer

EXPERIENCE

SMALL BUSINESS OWNER

The Nail Parlour, Everett WA 2010 - 2015 Glitterally Fabulous, San Diego, CA 2016 - 2018

Built several thriving nail salons from the ground up. Created original content for various social media sites for cross-platform promotion and exposure. Managed 6 employees.

- \$100,000 generated YOY while maintaining full-time clientele
- Voted Top Five Best Nail Salons in Best of Western Washington 2014-2015